<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v3.0 20080202//EN" "http://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/3.0/journalpublishing3.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="3.0" xml:lang="en">
<front>
<journal-meta>
<journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">PLoS ONE</journal-id>
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">plos</journal-id>
<journal-id journal-id-type="pmc">plosone</journal-id>
<journal-title-group>
<journal-title>PLOS ONE</journal-title>
</journal-title-group>
<issn pub-type="epub">1932-6203</issn>
<publisher>
<publisher-name>Public Library of Science</publisher-name>
<publisher-loc>San Francisco, CA USA</publisher-loc>
</publisher>
</journal-meta>
<article-meta>
<article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005</article-id>
<article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">PONE-D-14-55743</article-id>
<article-categories>
<subj-group subj-group-type="heading">
<subject>Research Article</subject>
</subj-group>
</article-categories>
<title-group>
<article-title>Neural Networks for Mindfulness and Emotion Suppression</article-title>
<alt-title alt-title-type="running-head">Neural Networks for Mindfulness and Emotion Suppression</alt-title>
</title-group>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="author" equal-contrib="yes" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Murakami</surname>
<given-names>Hiroki</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff001" ref-type="aff"><sup>1</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Katsunuma</surname>
<given-names>Ruri</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff002" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<xref rid="econtrib001" ref-type="fn"><sup>‡</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Oba</surname>
<given-names>Kentaro</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff002" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<xref rid="econtrib001" ref-type="fn"><sup>‡</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Terasawa</surname>
<given-names>Yuri</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff002" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<xref rid="econtrib001" ref-type="fn"><sup>‡</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Motomura</surname>
<given-names>Yuki</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff002" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<xref rid="econtrib001" ref-type="fn"><sup>‡</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Mishima</surname>
<given-names>Kazuo</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff002" ref-type="aff"><sup>2</sup></xref>
<xref rid="econtrib001" ref-type="fn"><sup>‡</sup></xref>
</contrib>
<contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" equal-contrib="yes" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Moriguchi</surname>
<given-names>Yoshiya</given-names>
</name>
<xref rid="aff003" ref-type="aff"><sup>3</sup></xref>
<xref rid="aff004" ref-type="aff"><sup>4</sup></xref>
<xref rid="cor001" ref-type="corresp">*</xref>
</contrib>
</contrib-group>
<aff id="aff001"><label>1</label> <addr-line>Integrated Neuroscience Research Project, Tokyo Metropolitan Institute of Medical Science, Tokyo, Japan</addr-line></aff>
<aff id="aff002"><label>2</label> <addr-line>Department of Psychophysiology, National Institute of Mental Health, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Kodaira, Tokyo, Japan</addr-line></aff>
<aff id="aff003"><label>3</label> <addr-line>Integrative Brain Imaging Center, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Kodaira, Tokyo, Japan</addr-line></aff>
<aff id="aff004"><label>4</label> <addr-line>Graduate School of Health Sciences, Gunma University, Maebashi, Gunma, Japan</addr-line></aff>
<contrib-group>
<contrib contrib-type="editor" xlink:type="simple">
<name name-style="western">
<surname>Kozlowski</surname>
<given-names>Gerald</given-names>
</name>
<role>Academic Editor</role>
<xref ref-type="aff" rid="edit1"/>
</contrib>
</contrib-group>
<aff id="edit1"><addr-line>Saybrook University, UNITED STATES</addr-line></aff>
<author-notes>
<fn fn-type="conflict" id="coi001">
<p>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</p>
</fn>
<fn fn-type="con" id="contrib001">
<p>Conceived and designed the experiments: HM Y. Moriguchi. Performed the experiments: HM Y. Moriguchi. Analyzed the data: HM Y. Moriguchi. Contributed reagents/materials/analysis tools: HM KM Y. Moriguchi. Wrote the paper: HM RK KO YT Y. Motomura KM Y. Moriguchi.</p>
</fn>
<fn fn-type="other" id="econtrib001">
<p>‡ These authors also contributed equally to this work.</p>
</fn>
<corresp id="cor001">* E-mail: <email xlink:type="simple">ymoriguchi@gunma-u.ac.jp</email></corresp>
</author-notes>
<pub-date pub-type="epub">
<day>17</day>
<month>6</month>
<year>2015</year>
</pub-date>
<pub-date pub-type="collection">
<year>2015</year>
</pub-date>
<volume>10</volume>
<issue>6</issue>
<elocation-id>e0128005</elocation-id>
<history>
<date date-type="received">
<day>17</day>
<month>12</month>
<year>2014</year>
</date>
<date date-type="accepted">
<day>21</day>
<month>4</month>
<year>2015</year>
</date>
</history>
<permissions>
<copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
<copyright-holder>Murakami et al</copyright-holder>
<license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" xlink:type="simple">
<license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" xlink:type="simple">Creative Commons Attribution License</ext-link>, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited</license-p>
</license>
</permissions>
<self-uri content-type="pdf" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005" xlink:type="simple"/>
<abstract>
<p>Mindfulness, an attentive non-judgmental focus on “here and now” experiences, has been incorporated into various cognitive behavioral therapy approaches and beneficial effects have been demonstrated. Recently, mindfulness has also been identified as a potentially effective emotion regulation strategy. On the other hand, emotion suppression, which refers to trying to avoid or escape from experiencing and being aware of one’s own emotions, has been identified as a potentially maladaptive strategy. Previous studies suggest that both strategies can decrease affective responses to emotional stimuli. They would, however, be expected to provide regulation through different top-down modulation systems. The present study was aimed at elucidating the different neural systems underlying emotion regulation via mindfulness and emotion suppression approaches. Twenty-one healthy participants used the two types of strategy in response to emotional visual stimuli while functional magnetic resonance imaging was conducted. Both strategies attenuated amygdala responses to emotional triggers, but the pathways to regulation differed across the two. A mindful approach appears to regulate amygdala functioning via functional connectivity from the medial prefrontal cortex, while suppression uses connectivity with other regions, including the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Thus, the two types of emotion regulation recruit different top-down modulation processes localized at prefrontal areas. These different pathways are discussed.</p>
</abstract>
<funding-group>
<funding-statement>This work was supported by JSPS KAKENHI Grant Number 25780438. The funders had no role in study design, data collection and analysis, decision to publish, or preparation of the manuscript.</funding-statement>
</funding-group>
<counts>
<fig-count count="5"/>
<table-count count="4"/>
<page-count count="18"/>
</counts>
<custom-meta-group>
<custom-meta id="data-availability" xlink:type="simple">
<meta-name>Data Availability</meta-name>
<meta-value>Data cannot be made publicly available as the authors did not obtain participant consent to do so. Please contact to the corresponding author “MORIGUCHI Yoshiya” to request the data.</meta-value>
</custom-meta>
</custom-meta-group>
</article-meta>
</front>
<body>
<sec id="sec001" sec-type="intro">
<title>Introduction</title>
<p>Emotion regulation is a fundamental function for human beings, as social animals, to adapt to the environment. There are a number of emotion regulation strategies, including emotion suppression, reappraisal [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>], distraction [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref002" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>], and detachment [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>]. Recently, <italic>mindfulness</italic> has received focus as an effective emotion regulation strategy [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref006" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. Mindfulness has been defined as “paying attention in a particular way: on purpose, in the present moment, and nonjudgmentally” (Kabat-Zinn, 1994, p. 4 [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref007" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]). More specifically, Baer et al. (2006) identified the central components of mindfulness, as described below. Mindfulness emphasizes the importance of observing a wide range of stimuli as a whole, including one’s own internal sensations as well as external phenomena outside the body. Moreover, mindfulness encourages describing observed phenomena, within the body and in the outer world, and engaging fully in one’s current activity with undivided attention, such that awareness is focused on one experience at a time, but not completely caught or involved in the experiences, i.e., focused attention with keeping some distance between oneself and the experiences. Additionally, mindfulness emphasizes accepting, allowing, or being nonjudgmental or nonevaluative about an experience in the present moment [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref008" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. These core components of mindfulness have been introduced to various cognitive behavioral therapy approaches, including Mindfulness-Based Cognitive Therapy (MBCT) [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>], Acceptance and Commitment Therapy (ACT) [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref010" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>], and Dialectical Behavior Therapy (DBT) [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref011" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>].</p>
<p>Beneficial effects of mindfulness training have been demonstrated in several studies. In a one-year follow-up study, mindfulness was shown to have significant efficacy in reducing relapse and recurrence of major depression, compared with treatment as usual [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. Another one-year follow-up study with breast and prostate cancer patients showed that mindfulness reduced stress-related indices such as inflammatory cytokines and cortisol as well as stress symptoms per se [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Baer (2003) suggested the possibility that mindfulness skill practice improves patients’ ability to effectively tolerate and cope with negative emotional states, by extinguishing fear responses and avoidance behaviors previously elicited by these stimuli [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref013" ref-type="bibr">13</xref>].</p>
<p>On the other hand, <italic>emotion suppression</italic> refers to attempts to avoid or escape from experiencing and being aware of one’s own emotions. Researchers have generally viewed emotion suppression as a maladaptive emotion regulation strategy [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>], such that individuals who frequently suppress experience less positive emotion, with a corresponding increased likelihood of experiencing negative emotions that are negatively associated with diverse aspects of psychosocial wellness [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref014" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Additionally, suppression of negative emotion promotes exaggerated sympathetic nervous system activity that can affect immune responses and physical health [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. Contrary to emotion suppression, mindfulness emphasizes an increasing awareness and full acceptance of all emotional experiences, regardless of apparent valence, intensity, or perceived utility [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref015" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>]. It is quite difficult for human beings to suppress feelings, given that affective changes <italic>per se</italic> are inherent and spontaneous, such that the acceptance of one’s own emotions should help one to stop endless and inefficient efforts to avoid emotional experiences. In fact, mindfulness increases parasympathetic nervous system activity and in essence ‘calms down’ systemic arousal [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref016" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], and thereby promotes therapeutic effects on psychopathological disorders [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>].</p>
<p>Understanding underlying mechanisms of mindfulness has been a hot topic in recent years, not only in clinical fields but also in neuroscience (see Tang &amp; Posner, 2013 [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref018" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]). Previous neuroimaging studies of mindfulness suggested that mindful participants show greater activation in the medial prefrontal cortex (MPFC) and lower activation in the amygdala (AMG) in response to emotional stimuli [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref019" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref020" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] Considering that the AMG plays a primary role in emotional responses [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref021" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>], these studies suggest that mindfulness improves emotion regulation via MPFC activity, which has an inhibitory effect on the AMG [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref022" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>–<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Electrical stimulation of the MPFC decreases the excitability of the projecting neurons from the central nucleus of the AMG to the brainstem, decreasing the expression of conditioned fear in rodents [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref025" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Similarly, MPFC functioning is related to extinction learning in human beings [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref026" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>].</p>
<p>In contrast, neuroimaging studies have not provided a conclusive answer regarding whether emotion suppression is effective in regulating emotional responses. One study showed marginally elevated AMG responding during expressive suppression (voluntarily suppressing outward emotional expressions) [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref027" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. However, another investigation showed that engaging in expressive suppression was effective in reducing AMG activity in response to emotional stimuli [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref028" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. Ohira et al. (2006) also showed that voluntary emotion suppression while viewing an affective stimulus successfully attenuates AMG responses, while simultaneously measured physiological emotional responding (peripheral skin conductance) was actually enhanced during the suppression task [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>].</p>
<p>Thus, evidence from neuroimaging studies suggests that both types of emotion regulation strategy–mindfulness and suppression–can possibly work to reduce AMG activity in response to emotional stimuli. However, the different strategies produce distinct patterns of peripheral emotional responses, such that mindfulness is associated with parasympathetic activity whereas suppression is correlated with sympathetic activity. This pattern could be due to processing differences between the two strategies, which would be expected to reflect different neural bases underlying the two strategies.</p>
<p>Contrary to the engagement of the MPFC during mindfulness, the lateral part of the prefrontal cortex typically contributes to the regulation of emotional responses during suppression [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref027" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref030" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. The emotional suppression process localized at the lateral prefrontal cortex might nevertheless be mentally stressful to engage. For example, the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC) is activated during working memory tasks [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref031" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>] that are frequently used to induce mental stress [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref032" ref-type="bibr">32</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref033" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>], and that such activation becomes more pronounced as task difficulty increases [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref034" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Such stressful cognitive processing may leave fewer cognitive resources available for concurrent emotional processing, which could work to control emotional responses even as cognitive stress may concurrently promote peripheral hyper-arousal. One plausible hypothesis here is that both mindfulness and suppression strategies can decrease AMG activity in response to emotional stimuli through different top-down modulation systems. No study, however, has directly compared the neural correlates of mindfulness and emotional suppression, which could provide further insight into the crucial components of emotion regulation.</p>
<p>The present study sought to elucidate neural differences between mindfulness and suppression emotion regulation strategies by way of a direct comparison between the two. We used functional connectivity analyses to identify different brain regions that contribute to regulating AMG responses during exposure to emotional stimuli, with the goal of identifying possible differences in the brain regions involved. AMG has been shown to have "negative" functional connectivity to the prefrontal cortex, and the MPFC in particular (e.g., [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>, <xref rid="pone.0128005.ref026" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref035" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]), as well as lateral prefrontal areas (e.g., [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref036" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref037" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>]). We expected that during mindfulness, the MPFC, which reportedly facilitates extinction learning, would be engaged to regulate AMG activation through negative functional coupling (i.e., negative correlation of time-series signals between the AMG and MPFC). On the other hand, during emotion suppression the lateral prefrontal cortex was expected to regulate AMG activation as a consequence of cognitive effort.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="sec002" sec-type="materials|methods">
<title>Materials and Methods</title>
<sec id="sec003">
<title>Participants</title>
<p>Twenty-one healthy, right-handed volunteers (10 men, 11 females, mean (±SD) age = 25.1 (±5.5) years, age range = 20–41 years) participated in the study. None of the participants reported a history of neurological or psychiatric disorders or current use of medication. All participants provided written informed consent in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki. The study was approved by the Ethics Committee of the National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Japan.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="sec004">
<title>Materials</title>
<p>Twenty-one neutral and 63 negative pictures were selected from the International Affective Picture System (IAPS), a data set that has been carefully characterized with respect to both valence and arousal [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref038" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>]. Based on normative ratings [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref038" ref-type="bibr">38</xref>], negative pictures were divided into three sets for use in the three task conditions described below, matched on emotional valence and arousal. Mean (SD) valence scores (1 = negative, 5 = neutral, 9 = positive) for the neutral and the three sets of negative pictures were 5.00 (SD = .51), 2.94 (.84), 2.87 (.72), and 2.93 (.90), respectively, and the scores did not differ between the three sets of negative pictures, <italic>F</italic>(2,60) = .046, <italic>p</italic> = .955. Mean (SD) arousal scores were 2.58 (.34), 6.04 (.60), 6.04 (.77) and 6.02 (.70), respectively, and again three were no differences between the negative sets, <italic>F</italic>(2,60) = .004, <italic>p</italic> = .997. We had the participants rate the pictures prior to the fMRI study, confirming that the pictures had similar valence and arousal values for the participants in our study: Mean (SD) valence scores were 5.20 (.23), 3.11 (.53), 2.94 (.57), and 3.10 (.59), respectively, and the scores did not differ across the three sets of negative pictures <italic>F</italic>(3,20) = .629, <italic>p</italic> = .536, and the mean (SD) arousal scores were 2.56 (1.15), 6.27 (.90), 6.50 (.79) and 6.16 (.90), respectively, with no differences across the latter three sets, <italic>F</italic>(3,20) = .892, <italic>p</italic> = .415.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="sec005">
<title>Procedure</title>
<p>Blood oxygen level dependent (BOLD) signal changes were measured during four experimental tasks: Look-neutral, Look-negative, Suppress-negative, and Observe-negative. During Look-neutral and Look-negative tasks, the participants were required to simply look at the neutral or negative pictures and respond naturally. During Suppress-negative, the participants were required to voluntarily suppress any emotional responses to viewing negative pictures. Specifically, they were required to try to "remain calm and to diminish any subjective feelings regardless of the affective valence of the stimulus", which followed the procedure used by Ohira et al. (2006) [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. During the Observe-negative task, a mindfulness intervention, participants were required to "observe objectively and describe their subjective feelings or thoughts in their minds, and physiological changes in bodies, not with voice but just mentally, and to <italic>not</italic> suppress the emotions that are evoked by viewing the negative pictures". Before entering the MRI scanner, participants were carefully instructed regarding how to cope with the presented affective pictures using the three strategies (i.e., Look, Suppress, and Observe).</p>
<p>The participants each took part in three fMRI runs, each of which consisted of 28 trials. Each trial was composed of four successive events as follows. First, a cue word (“Look”, “Suppress”, or “Observe”) appeared centrally on the screen for 2 s right before the presentation of an IAPS picture. Only neutral pictures were presented during the Look-neutral task, while negative pictures were presented during the other tasks. During the same period, picture valence ("neutral" or "negative") was shown below the cue word to avoid potential effects of uncertainty of picture valances across the task conditions [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref039" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. Second, a neutral or negative picture appeared centrally for 8 s. While the picture remained on the screen, participants were required to perform the coping strategy/action specified by the prior cue. Third, a 9-point Likert scale (1 = none, 9 = extremely) appeared immediately after presentation of the picture. This scale allowed the participants to rate the current strength of subjective negative affect in their own mind after experiencing the picture stimulus while engaging in the indicated coping strategy. Participants provided these ratings by moving an MRI-compatible trackball. Fourth, a fixation cross appeared for 4 s in the center of the screen, indicating that participants should relax until the next trial began. In each run the order of the four task conditions (Look-neutral, Look-negative, Suppress-negative, and Observe-negative) was presented pseudorandom order in an event related design. We counterbalanced set of negative pictures used in each task condition across participants.</p>
<p>After fMRI scanning, we asked the participants whether they had successfully observed themselves objectively using the following question: “How much did you observe yourself objectively during the [Look, Suppress, or Observe] task in the scanner?” They rated themselves, separately for each task condition, using 9-point Likert scales (1 = not at all, 9 = very much so). We expected them to report greater levels of objective observation during the Observe task than during the other tasks. We dubbed this score “objective perspective” and used it to assess whether the Observe task successfully induced a mindful state.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="sec006">
<title>Image Acquisition and Analyses</title>
<p>Magnetic resonance images were acquired on a 1.5-T Siemens Magnetom Vision Plus System. To obtain a blood-oxygenation-level dependent (BOLD) contrast for functional imaging [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref040" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>], changes in the T2*-weighted magnetic resonance (MR) signal were measured using a gradient echo-planar imaging (EPI) sequence (repetition time (TR) = 2500 ms, echo time (TE) = 40 ms, field of view (FOV) = 192 mm, flip angle = 90 degree, 64 × 64 matrix, 31 slices per slab, slice thickness 4 mm, 1 mm gap, voxel size = 3 × 3 × 4 mm). For each scanning run, a total of 236 EPI volume images were acquired along the AC-PC plane. The first five EPI image volumes were discarded because of magnetization instability, such that we obtained 231 EPI volumes for analyses.</p>
<p>Image processing and statistical analyses were carried out using Statistical Parametric Mapping software (SPM8, Wellcome Department, London, UK). Preprocessing of the functional scans included realignment for motion correction using the first scan as a reference and spatial normalization to a standard template (Montreal Neurological Institute, MNI), with a resampled voxel size of 2 × 2 × 2 mm. The normalized images were smoothed using an 8-mm FWHM Gaussian kernel. Intrinsic autocorrelations were accounted for by AR(1) and low frequency drifts were removed via high pass filter (128 s). The 2 s instruction period, the 8 s regulation period, and 6 s rating period were modeled as a delayed boxcar regressor convolved with the canonical hemodynamic response. The time-course imaging data were regressed using a linear combination of the differential hypothetical hemodynamic time-courses of different event types on a voxel-by-voxel basis. This general linear model (GLM) analysis produced contrast images for each participant which included the differential parameter estimates between task conditions, which were taken to a second-level random effects model for group analyses.</p>
<p>To identify emotion-related brain regions, we first sought significantly-activated clusters for Look-negative contrasted with Look-neutral (height threshold, <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, extent threshold, <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels), and made a 3mm-sphere region of interest (ROI) centered on the peak of the cluster. We calculated individual mean contrast values for 1) Look-negative vs. Look-neutral, 2) Suppress-negative vs. Look-negative, and 3) Observe-negative vs. Look-negative within the ROI using Marsbar software (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://marsbar.sourceforge.net" xlink:type="simple">http://marsbar.sourceforge.net</ext-link>).</p>
<p>To identify brain regions remotely connected to emotional regions above, voxel-based and ROI-based correlational analyses were performed using the Functional Connectivity toolbox (CONN; <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.nitrc.org/projects/conn/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.nitrc.org/projects/conn/</ext-link>). After pre-processing of functional images, time-series data for each voxel were filtered with a band-pass of .01 – .20 Hz. This band-pass range had been optimized to capture effective hemodynamic changes by use of the spectral analyses of the aforementioned GLM model. The CONN toolbox was used to perform seed-based functional connectivity analysis, by computing Fisher-transformed bivariate temporal correlation coefficients between BOLD time series at a given ROI and those at all other voxels in the brain. The toolbox also extracts signals from the white matter (WM) and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF), which should reflect physiological fluctuation. Then, WM and CSF signals, together with motion parameters, were regressed out as nuisance variables during the functional connectivity analyses. We created a correlational brain map, each voxel of which contains the functional connectivity between that voxel and the seed ROI.</p>
<p>Finally, to identify differential functional connectivity that might produce differential emotional responses between the two strategies, we investigated the relationship between the magnitude of activation at the emotional ROI and the functional connectivity to that ROI. We calculated individual functional connectivity to the ROI during each Suppress-, Observe-, and Look-negative strategy, then contrasted the first two with the last (i.e., Suppress vs. Look, Observe vs. Look). And individual regional responses during Suppress and Observe (contrasted with Look) were also extracted from the ROI. These regional responses to Suppress and Observe were correlated with the differential functional connectivity (height threshold, <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, extent threshold, <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels).</p>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="sec007" sec-type="results">
<title>Results</title>
<sec id="sec008">
<title>Behavioral results</title>
<p>We first confirmed whether our experimental instructions for the Observe task were successful. A one-way ANOVA (Look / Suppress / Observe) conducted on the objective perspective scores showed a significant difference across the three tasks: Mean (and standard deviations) scores for the Look, Suppress, and Observe tasks were 2.29 (1.34), 3.05 (1.49), and 6.76 (1.26), respectively, <italic>F</italic> (2, 40) = 86.83, <italic>p</italic> = 1×10<sup>-14</sup>, <italic>η</italic><sup>2</sup><sub><italic>p</italic></sub> = .81. Specifically, objective perspective scores were significantly greater for the Observe task than for the other tasks (compared with Look, <italic>T</italic>(20) = 12.32, <italic>p</italic> = 7×10<sup>-10</sup>; with Suppress, <italic>T</italic>(20) = 10.22, <italic>p</italic> = 1×10<sup>-8</sup>, after Bonferroni correction), indicating that the participants felt that they could observe themselves objectively during the appropriate task.</p>
<p>Participants’ negative affect scores were significantly different after engaging in the four tasks, <italic>M</italic> (<italic>SD</italic>) = 1.61 (.87), 5.39 (1.41), 4.59 (1.35) and 4.50 (1.16) for Look-neutral, Look-negative, Suppress-negative, and Observe-negative, respectively, <italic>F</italic> (3,60) = 95.11, <italic>p</italic> = 9×10<sup>-23</sup>, <italic>η</italic><sup>2</sup><sub><italic>p</italic></sub> = .89 (see <xref rid="pone.0128005.g001" ref-type="fig">Fig 1</xref>). We confirmed that presentation of the negative pictures enhanced negative emotionality in the participants: Negative affect scores after the Look-neutral task were significantly lower than scores for the other three tasks where negative pictures were presented (<italic>t</italic>(20) = 11.99, <italic>p</italic> = 1×10<sup>-10</sup> for comparison with Look-negative, <italic>t</italic>(20) = 10.34, <italic>p</italic> = 2×10<sup>-9</sup> for comparison with Suppress-negative, and <italic>t</italic>(20) = 12.08, <italic>p</italic> = 1×10<sup>-10</sup> for comparison with Observe-negative, after Bonferroni correction). Importantly, both suppression and observation strategies were effective for regulation of emotion: Negative affect scores after Suppress-negative (<italic>t</italic>(20) = 3.33, <italic>p</italic> = .001, with Bonferroni correction) and Observe-negative (<italic>t</italic>(20) = 3.73, <italic>p</italic> = .001, with Bonferroni correction) task were lower than scores after the Look-negative task.</p>
<fig id="pone.0128005.g001" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g001</object-id>
<label>Fig 1</label>
<caption>
<title>VAS scores for negative affect after each coping strategy (bars represent standard errors).</title>
<p>Significant differences were found for the comparisons of Look-neutral vs. other conditions and Look-negative vs. Suppress-negative, and Observe-negative. The two types of emotion regulation strategies were effective for regulation of subjective emotion.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g001" position="float" xlink:type="simple"/>
</fig>
</sec>
<sec id="sec009">
<title>fMRI results</title>
<sec id="sec010">
<title>Neural response in the AMG in different coping strategies</title>
<p>The whole brain analysis for the contrast between Look-negative and Look-neutral showed activations in emotion-related brain areas such as the AMG and midbrain, as well as other regions such as the occipital gyrus, prefrontal cortex, and dorsal anterior cingulate cortex (dACC) (<xref rid="pone.0128005.s001" ref-type="supplementary-material">S1 Table</xref>). As expected, the left AMG showed a robust response to the affective stimuli (Look-negative vs. Look-neutral contrast; <italic>t</italic>(60) = 3.71, <italic>p</italic> = .0002 (uncorrected), cluster <italic>k</italic> = 9 voxels; peak MNI coordinate (mm) <italic>x</italic> = −34, <italic>y</italic> = −8, <italic>z</italic> = −22; <xref rid="pone.0128005.g002" ref-type="fig">Fig 2</xref>). The AMG has been frequently described as the center of emotional processing in the brain [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref021" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref025" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>], such that we focused this region, creating a 3-mm sphere ROI centered on the peak coordinate.</p>
<fig id="pone.0128005.g002" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g002</object-id>
<label>Fig 2</label>
<caption>
<title>Left AMG [-34, -8, -22] response to affective stimuli (Look-negative vs. Look-neutral contrast (<italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected for illustration)).</title>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g002" position="float" xlink:type="simple"/>
</fig>
<p>AMG responses while viewing negative pictures (Look-negative, Suppress-negative, and Observe-negative) were significantly different from each other, <italic>F</italic> (2, 40) = 5.92, <italic>p</italic> = .009, <italic>η</italic><sup>2</sup><sub><italic>p</italic></sub> = .23 (<xref rid="pone.0128005.g003" ref-type="fig">Fig 3</xref>). More specifically, AMG responding during Suppress-negative was significantly lower than during Look-negative, <italic>t</italic>(20) = 3.44, <italic>p</italic> = .0014, such that suppression was effective to regulate emotional responding in the AMG. AMG responding during Observe-negative was marginally lower than responding during Look-negative, <italic>t</italic>(20) = 1.57, <italic>p</italic> = .12, which suggests that the observation strategy also worked to regulate emotional responding in the AMG although the effect was marginal, and marginally less robust than the effect of suppression <italic>t</italic>(20) = 2.51, <italic>p</italic> = .06 (Suppress-Negative vs. Observe-Negative).</p>
<fig id="pone.0128005.g003" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g003</object-id>
<label>Fig 3</label>
<caption>
<title>Neural response in the left AMG ROI in each condition (bars represent standard errors).</title>
<p>The response to Look-negative was significantly stronger than the response to Look-neutral. The response to Suppress-negative and Observe-negative was significantly lower than the response to Look-negative, although the difference between Observe-negative and Look-negative was marginal.</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g003" position="float" xlink:type="simple"/>
</fig>
</sec>
<sec id="sec011">
<title>Whole brain analysis for effect of emotion regulation</title>
<p>To examine the effect of emotion regulation in the whole brain, we computed Suppress-negative &gt; Look-negative (<xref rid="pone.0128005.t001" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref> and <xref rid="pone.0128005.g004" ref-type="fig">Fig 4A</xref>) and Observe-negative &gt; Look-negative contrasts (<xref rid="pone.0128005.t002" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref> and <xref rid="pone.0128005.g004" ref-type="fig">Fig 4B</xref>). We found greater activation for Suppress-negative compared to Look-negative in the left inferior frontal gyrus (IFG; Brodmann area (BA) 47). In contrast, during Observe-negative compared to Look-negative, there was greater activation in the precentral gyrus (BA6), IFG (BA44), superior frontal gyrus (SFG; BA6/8), middle temporal gyrus (MTG; BA21/22), inferior parietal lobule (IPL; BA40), putamen, and anterior insula (AI; BA13). These results suggest completely differential neural correlates for the two coping strategies studied here, such that observational (mindful) coping seems to engage wider neural networks than does suppression.</p>
<fig id="pone.0128005.g004" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g004</object-id>
<label>Fig 4</label>
<caption>
<title>Neural activity for Suppress-negative (A) and Observe-negative (B) contrasted with Look-negative (<italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected).</title>
<p>Regions with significantly greater activation in Suppress-negative compared to Look-negative condition included the left inferior frontal gyrus (IFG; BA47). During Observe-negative compared to Look-negative, there was greater activation in the precentral gyrus (BA6), IFG (BA44), superior frontal gyrus (SFG; BA6/8), middle temporal gyrus (MTG; BA21/22), inferior parietal lobule (IPL; BA40), putamen, and anterior insula (AI; BA13).</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g004" position="float" xlink:type="simple"/>
</fig>
<table-wrap id="pone.0128005.t001" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t001</object-id>
<label>Table 1</label> <caption><title>Coordinates for the brain areas activated in Suppress-negative vs. Look-negative.</title></caption>
<alternatives>
<graphic id="pone.0128005.t001g" position="float" mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t001" xlink:type="simple"/>
<table>
<colgroup span="1">
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Area</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BA</th>
<th colspan="3" align="center" rowspan="1">MNI coordinates (mm)</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>T</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cluster size, <italic>k</italic></th>
</tr>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>x</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>y</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Suppress negative &gt; Look negative</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Inferior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.74</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.53</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Inferior Parietal Lobule</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">64</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.72</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Inferior Parietal Lobule</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-62</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.52</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.34</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</alternatives>
<table-wrap-foot>
<fn id="t001fn001"><p>Height threshold: <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, Extent threshold: <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels. The x, y, and z coordinates by which a voxel is determined referring to medial–lateral (x: positive = right), anterior–posterior (y: positive = anterior), and superior–inferior (z: positive = superior) positions denote the peak location on the MNI template. T-scores denote the difference between the two sample means compared with the dispersion and sample sizes of the two samples.Z-scores are the numbers from the unit normal distribution that give the same p value as the t statistic. Abbreviations: BA = Brodmann area; MNI = Montreal Neurological Institute template.</p></fn>
</table-wrap-foot>
</table-wrap>
<table-wrap id="pone.0128005.t002" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t002</object-id>
<label>Table 2</label> <caption><title>Coordinates of the brain areas activated in Observe-negative vs. Look-negative.</title></caption>
<alternatives>
<graphic id="pone.0128005.t002g" position="float" mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t002" xlink:type="simple"/>
<table>
<colgroup span="1">
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Area</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BA</th>
<th colspan="3" align="center" rowspan="1">MNI coordinates (mm)</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>T</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cluster size, <italic>k</italic></th>
</tr>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>x</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>y</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Observe negative &gt; Look negative</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Precentral Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">8.25</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.72</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3980</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-6</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.58</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.69</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Inferior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.22</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-4</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">64</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.99</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.57</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2802</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-10</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.74</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.11</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">52</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.57</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.98</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Middle Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-52</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-36</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.51</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.28</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1958</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Inferior Parietal Lobule</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.35</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.82</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Middle Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.63</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.72</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">334</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Lentiform Nucleus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.84</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">751</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Lentiform Nucleus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-2</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.56</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.21</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Insula</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.53</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Cerebellum</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-68</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-24</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.79</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.14</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">1777</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Cerebellum</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-62</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-28</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.54</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.96</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Cerebellum</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-66</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-50</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.24</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.73</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Cingulate Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.49</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.15</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">63</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Inferior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.04</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.78</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">141</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Inferior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.92</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.68</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Lentiform Nucleus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.98</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.73</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Caudate</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.77</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.56</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.94</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.7</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">74</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Cerebellum</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-60</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-22</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.44</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.28</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</alternatives>
<table-wrap-foot>
<fn id="t002fn001"><p>Height threshold: <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, Extent threshold: <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels. The x, y, and z coordinates by which a voxel is determined referring to medial–lateral (x: positive = right), anterior–posterior (y: positive = anterior), and superior–inferior (z: positive = superior) positions denote the peak location on the MNI template. T-scores denote the difference between the two sample means compared with the dispersion and sample sizes of the two samples. Z-scores are the numbers from the unit normal distribution that give the same p value as the t statistic. Abbreviations: BA = Brodmann area; MNI = Montreal Neurological Institute template.</p></fn>
</table-wrap-foot>
</table-wrap>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="sec012">
<title>Functional connectivity with the AMG</title>
<p>AMG activity differences across individuals should be produced by individual differences in functional connectivity from remote regions to the AMG. In addition, the relationship between AMG activity and functional connectivity should depend on coping strategies. As expected, we found that during the Observe-negative condition (compared to Look-negative), individual AMG-MPFC connectivities were most correlated with left AMG activity across individuals, in a positive direction (<italic>r</italic>(19) = .87, <italic>p</italic> = 4×10<sup>-7</sup>, <xref rid="pone.0128005.t003" ref-type="table">Table 3</xref> and <xref rid="pone.0128005.g005" ref-type="fig">Fig 5(B)</xref>). As noted previously, the AMG has negative functional connectivity to the MPFC, and the present results mean that stronger negative functional connectivity accompanies more attenuated AMG activity (and vice versa; i.e., stronger positive functional connectivity accompanies stronger AMG activity). On the other hand, during the Suppress-negative task (contrasted with the Look-negative task), individual left AMG activity was positively correlated with multiple connectivities to remote regions (see <xref rid="pone.0128005.t004" ref-type="table">Table 4</xref>). These include AMG-DLPFC and AMG-precuneus connectivity (<italic>r</italic>(19) = .76, <italic>p</italic> = .00007 and <italic>r</italic>(19) = .75, <italic>p</italic> = .0001, respectively; <xref rid="pone.0128005.g005" ref-type="fig">Fig 5(A)</xref>). These results indicate that functional connectivity to the AMG correlates with AMG activity in ways that differ between suppressive and observational coping: AMG activity was attenuated via negative MPFC-AMG connectivity for the observational strategy, but via negative DLPFC-AMG and precuneus-AMG connectivity for the suppression strategy.</p>
<fig id="pone.0128005.g005" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g005</object-id>
<label>Fig 5</label>
<caption>
<title>Correlation between regional AMG activity and functional connectivity to the AMG.</title>
<p>The figures show brain regions that have more negative functional connectivity with the AMG when AMG responses were reduced during Suppress-negative (A) and Observe-negative (B) contrasted with Look-negative (<italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected).</p>
</caption>
<graphic mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.g005" position="float" xlink:type="simple"/>
</fig>
<table-wrap id="pone.0128005.t003" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t003</object-id>
<label>Table 3</label> <caption><title>Coordinates of the brain areas activated in Observe-negative vs. Look-negative.</title></caption>
<alternatives>
<graphic id="pone.0128005.t003g" position="float" mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t003" xlink:type="simple"/>
<table>
<colgroup span="1">
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Area</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BA</th>
<th colspan="3" align="center" rowspan="1">MNI coordinates (mm)</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>T</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cluster size, <italic>k</italic></th>
</tr>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>x</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>y</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Observe negative &gt; Look negative</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7.52</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.06</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">135</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Medial Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.61</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.73</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Uncus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-14</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-30</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.97</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.43</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">21</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">36</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.33</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.37</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Insula</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-38</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.02</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.95</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Superior Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-40</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.76</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.81</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Parahippocampal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-26</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.52</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.68</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Inferior Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">16</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.19</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</alternatives>
<table-wrap-foot>
<fn id="t003fn001"><p>Height threshold: <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, Extent threshold: <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels. The x, y, and z coordinates by which a voxel is determined referring to medial–lateral (x: positive = right), anterior–posterior (y: positive = anterior), and superior–inferior (z: positive = superior) positions denote the peak location on the MNI template. T-scores denote the difference between the two sample means compared with the dispersion and sample sizes of the two samples. Z-scores are the numbers from the unit normal distribution that give the same p value as the t statistic. Abbreviations: BA = Brodmann area; MNI = Montreal Neurological Institute template.</p></fn>
</table-wrap-foot>
</table-wrap>
<table-wrap id="pone.0128005.t004" position="float">
<object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t004</object-id>
<label>Table 4</label> <caption><title>Coordinates of the brain areas whose connectivity with the amygdala was positively correlated with regional amygdala activity during Suppress-negative vs. Look-negative.</title></caption>
<alternatives>
<graphic id="pone.0128005.t004g" position="float" mimetype="image" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.t004" xlink:type="simple"/>
<table>
<colgroup span="1">
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
<col align="left" valign="middle" span="1"/>
</colgroup>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Area</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">BA</th>
<th colspan="3" align="center" rowspan="1">MNI coordinates (mm)</th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>T</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>Z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Cluster size, <italic>k</italic></th>
</tr>
<tr>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>x</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>y</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"><italic>z</italic></th>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<th align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Suppress negative &gt; Look negative</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Superior Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-48</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-10</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-6</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.14</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.02</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Caudate</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.13</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.01</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Middle Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">28</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">5.06</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.98</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Postcentral Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">64</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.89</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.88</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">20</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Superior Parietal Lobule</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-70</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.87</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.88</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Thalamus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-2</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">2</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.78</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.83</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Postcentral Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-44</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-28</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.77</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.82</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Fusiform Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-68</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-20</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.7</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.78</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Cingulate Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.63</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.74</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Precentral Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-42</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-10</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.61</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.73</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Precuneus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-56</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">34</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.49</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.66</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Middle Temporal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">39</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-50</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-80</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.48</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.65</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Middle Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-8</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">64</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.32</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.56</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">14</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Cingulate Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-2</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.11</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.43</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Posterior Cingulate</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-60</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">24</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">4.03</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.39</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Left Middle Frontal Gyrus</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-18</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-4</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.96</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.34</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Right Superior Parietal Lobule</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">-56</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.92</td>
<td align="char" char="." rowspan="1" colspan="1">3.32</td>
<td align="left" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</alternatives>
<table-wrap-foot>
<fn id="t004fn001"><p>Height threshold: <italic>p</italic> &lt; .001 uncorrected, Extent threshold: <italic>k</italic> = 5 voxels. The x, y, and z coordinates by which a voxel is determined referring to medial–lateral (x: positive = right), anterior–posterior (y: positive = anterior), and superior–inferior (z: positive = superior) positions denote the peak location on the MNI template. T-scores denote the difference between the two sample means compared with the dispersion and sample sizes of the two samples. Z-scores are the numbers from the unit normal distribution that give the same p value as the t statistic. Abbreviations: BA = Brodmann area; MNI = Montreal Neurological Institute template.</p></fn>
</table-wrap-foot>
</table-wrap>
</sec>
</sec>
<sec id="sec013" sec-type="conclusions">
<title>Discussion</title>
<p>The purpose of the present study was to examine the different neural systems underlying mindful and suppression-based emotion regulation. Subjective negative affect scores showed that both emotion regulation strategies were effective in regulating negative emotion in response to negative stimuli, consistent with evidence from previous studies of emotion suppression [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>] and mindfulness [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref004" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>–<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref006" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. There were corresponding decreases in AMG responses for both emotion regulation strategies. These results showed that both emotion regulation strategies were effective to regulate emotional neural responses as well as subjective emotion in response to negative stimuli.</p>
<p>The suppression strategy in our study activated the ventrolateral prefrontal cortex (VLPFC), which is in line with evidence that the VLPFC plays a primary role in suppressing emotion [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref027" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref030" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>]. In contrast, a broader range of brain areas were deployed during the Observe (mindful) condition. The superior frontal gyrus is engaged in ‘detachment’ during emotion regulation, as reported in previous studies [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref003" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref041" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>]. The Observe strategy used in our study involves taking an objective perspective regarding one’s own internal states. The participants therefore distanced themselves from their own states. Additionally, the dACC was activated during the Observe condition. The dACC is associated with attention [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref042" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>] and the ability to accurately detect emotional signals [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref043" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>], verifying that the participants in our study attended to the presented pictures instead of avoiding them, with a corresponding increased awareness of their emotional experience. The activation of the anterior insula (AI) also suggests that the participants mindfully experienced their emotional states without avoidance in the Observe condition, considering that the AI processes interoceptive information important for emotional awareness [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref044" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref045" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>], with its structural development closely connected to mindfulness [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref046" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>–<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref048" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>]. In sum, the Observe strategy seems to recruit neural networks involved in multiple cognitive/emotional processes, including detachment, attention, and emotional awareness.</p>
<p>In the Observe condition, participants were also instructed to describe their own states of mind using their inner voice. This may account for why we found activation in language areas such as the left inferior frontal gyrus, including Broca’s area and the bilateral middle temporal gyrus [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref049" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>–<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref051" ref-type="bibr">51</xref>]. Mindfulness involves verbal labeling as a useful tool for self-awareness [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref019" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. The present results suggest that the labeling play an important role in the regulation of emotion during use of an observational coping strategy.</p>
<p>Functional connectivity analyses were conducted to investigate the different neural systems underlying the two types of emotion regulation strategy. Our results revealed that largely different functional connectivity modulates AMG activity during use of the two strategies. Note that the DLPFC and the precuneus contributed to regulation of amygdala responses via functional connectivity in the Suppression condition. Reportedly, the DLPFC is activated during the tasks requiring cognitive effort [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref030" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>], which leads to enhancement of sympathetic nervous activity [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref052" ref-type="bibr">52</xref>]. This is consistent with evidence from previous emotion suppression studies, which showed increased peripheral responses during suppression [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref001" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref014" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref029" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Additionally, the precuneus underlies the default mode network in the resting brain, the activation of which is attenuated during cognitive task performance [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref053" ref-type="bibr">53</xref>]. One possibility is that when participants try to suppress their negative emotional responses, they might avoid processing external stimuli. This notion is supported by a study which investigated the association between precuneus activation and visual avoidance as measured by eye tracking while spider phobic participants were presented pictures of spiders [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref054" ref-type="bibr">54</xref>].</p>
<p>On the other hand, the MPFC contributed to regulation of amygdala responses in the Observe condition. In most cases, the amygdala has negative functional connectivity with the MPFC (e.g., [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref023" ref-type="bibr">23</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref024" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref026" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref035" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]). In animal studies, electrical stimulation of the MPFC decreases the excitability of the central nucleus of the amygdala [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref055" ref-type="bibr">55</xref>], and the MPFC is reported to contribute to extinction learning in human studies [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref026" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>]. One possible presumption here is that the mechanism of emotion regulation in mindfulness may include extinction learning. Additionally, in the mindful coping strategy, the participants accept their emotions instead of requiring the cognitive effort represented by activation in the DLPFC. Moreover, the mindful coping strategy seemed to activate the parasympathetic nervous system [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref017" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>], which is known to be modulated by MPFC activity [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref056" ref-type="bibr">56</xref>]. Therefore, the mindful coping strategy in the present study might be associated with parasympathetic activity as well as regulating AMG responses via the MPFC. These neural mechanisms may promote therapeutic effects on psychopathology [<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref009" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="pone.0128005.ref012" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. Future studies should simultaneously measure peripheral responses and brain activity during mindfulness.</p>
<p>The present study is constrained by one limitation. Although the Observe strategy was effective for regulating both emotional neural responses and subjective emotions in response to negative stimuli, the statistical power of the effect was low. Therefore, it is suggested that this relationship should be further examined in future studies using a larger sample of participants.</p>
<p>To our knowledge, this is the first time that the two types of emotion regulation—mindfulness and suppression—were compared in a single study. Both strategies attenuated AMG responses, to some extent, to emotional triggers but the regulation pathways were different: The mindful approach regulates AMG responding via connectivity from the MPFC, which is an important region for emotional awareness and mindfulness, while suppression uses functional connectivity with other regions including the DLPFC and precuneus, which should be involved in more top-down regulatory processing and which therefore requires more cognitive effort.</p>
<p>IAPS identification numbers for the pictures used. Neutral pictures: 1670, 2190, 2393, 2570, 5530, 7004, 7006, 7010, 7020, 7035, 7041, 7050, 7100, 7179, 7205, 7217, 7224, 7491, 7705, 7950, 9360. Negative pictures set 1: 1022, 1052, 1114, 1220, 1274, 1310, 1932, 3100, 3120, 3550, 6243, 6260, 6360, 6560, 6831, 7380, 8485, 9102, 9250, 9320, 9594. set 2: 1051, 1113, 1270, 1300, 1930, 2120, 3071, 3110, 3500, 6230, 6250, 6315, 6530, 6571, 7361, 8480, 9140, 9301, 9400, 9440, 9635.1. set 3: 1050, 1070, 1120, 1200 1230, 1275, 1525, 2095, 2220, 3030, 3101, 3130, 6212, 6244, 6300, 6510, 6570, 7359, 8230, 9300, 9630.</p>
</sec>
<sec id="sec014">
<title>Supporting Information</title>
<supplementary-material id="pone.0128005.s001" xlink:href="info:doi/10.1371/journal.pone.0128005.s001" mimetype="application/msword" position="float" xlink:type="simple">
<label>S1 Table</label>
<caption>
<title>Coordinates for the brain areas activated in Look-negative vs. Look-neutral.</title>
<p>(DOC)</p>
</caption>
</supplementary-material>
</sec>
</body>
<back>
<ref-list>
<title>References</title>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref001"><label>1</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gross</surname> <given-names>JJ</given-names></name> (<year>2002</year>) <article-title>Emotion regulation: affective, cognitive, and social consequences</article-title>. <source>Psychophysiology</source>, <volume>39</volume>, <fpage>281</fpage>–<lpage>291</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">12212647</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref002"><label>2</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tracey</surname> <given-names>I</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ploghau</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gati</surname> <given-names>JS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Clare</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Menon</surname> <given-names>RS</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2002</year>) <article-title>Imaging attentional modulation of pain in the periaqueductal gray in humans</article-title>. <source>Journal of Neuroscience</source>. <volume>22</volume>, <fpage>2748</fpage>–<lpage>2752</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">11923440</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref003"><label>3</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Beauregard</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lévesque</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Bourgouin</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name> (<year>2001</year>) <article-title>Neural correlates of conscious self-regulation of emotion</article-title>. <source>Journal of Neuroscience</source>, <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>RC165</fpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">11549754</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref004"><label>4</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Arch</surname> <given-names>JJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Craske</surname> <given-names>MG</given-names></name> (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>Mechanisms of mindfulness: emotion regulation following a focused breaching induction</article-title>. <source>Behaviour Research and Therapy</source>, <volume>44</volume>, <fpage>1849</fpage>–<lpage>1858</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16460668</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref005"><label>5</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldin</surname> <given-names>PR</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gross</surname> <given-names>JJ</given-names></name> (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>Effects of mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR) on emotion regulation in social anxiety disorder</article-title>. <source>Emotion</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>83</fpage>–<lpage>91</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0018441" xlink:type="simple">10.1037/a0018441</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">20141305</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref006"><label>6</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hayes</surname> <given-names>AM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Feldman</surname> <given-names>GC</given-names></name> (<year>2004</year>) <article-title>Clarifying the Construct of Mindfulness in the Context of Emotion Regulation and the Process of Change in Therapy</article-title>. <source>Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice</source>, <volume>11</volume>, <fpage>255</fpage>–<lpage>262</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref007"><label>7</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Kabat-Zinn</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name> (<year>1982</year>) <article-title>An outpatient program in behavioral medicine for chronic pain patients based on the practice of mindfulness meditation: theoretical considerations and preliminary results</article-title>. <source>General Hospital Psychiatry</source>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>33</fpage>–<lpage>47</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">7042457</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref008"><label>8</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Baer</surname> <given-names>RA</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname> <given-names>GT</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hopkins</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Krietemeyer</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Toney</surname> <given-names>L</given-names></name> (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>Using self-report assessment methods to explore facets of mindfulness</article-title>. <source>Assessment</source>, <volume>13</volume>, <fpage>27</fpage>–<lpage>45</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16443717</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref009"><label>9</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Teasdale</surname> <given-names>JD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Segal</surname> <given-names>ZV</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Williams</surname> <given-names>JM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ridgeway</surname> <given-names>VA</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Soulsby</surname> <given-names>JM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lau</surname> <given-names>MA</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2000</year>) <article-title>Prevention of relapse/recurrence in major depression by mindfulness-based cognitive therapy</article-title>. <source>Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology</source>, <volume>68</volume>, <fpage>615</fpage>–<lpage>623</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">10965637</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref010"><label>10</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hayes</surname> <given-names>SC</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Strosahl</surname> <given-names>KD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wilson</surname> <given-names>KG</given-names></name> (<year>1999</year>) <source>Acceptance and commitment therapy: An experiential approach to behavior change</source>. <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Guilford Press</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref011"><label>11</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Linehan</surname> <given-names>MM</given-names></name> (<year>1993</year>) <source>Cognitive Behavioral Treatment of Borderline Personality Disorder</source>. <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>: <publisher-name>Guilford Press</publisher-name>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref012"><label>12</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Carlson</surname> <given-names>LE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Speca</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Faris</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Patel</surname> <given-names>KD</given-names></name> (<year>2007</year>) <article-title>One year pre-post intervention follow-up of psychological, immune, endocrine and blood pressure outcomes of mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR) in breast and prostate cancer outpatients</article-title>. <source>Brain, Behavior, and Immunity</source>, <volume>21</volume>, <fpage>1038</fpage>–<lpage>1049</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">17521871</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref013"><label>13</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Baer</surname> <given-names>RA</given-names></name> (<year>2003</year>) <article-title>Mindfulness training as a clinical intervention: A conceptual and empirical review</article-title>. <source>Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>125</fpage>–<lpage>143</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref014"><label>14</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gross</surname> <given-names>JJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>John</surname> <given-names>OP</given-names></name> (<year>2003</year>) <article-title>Individual differences in two emotion regulation processes: implications for affect, relationships, and well-being</article-title>. <source>Journal of Personality and Social psychology</source>, <volume>85</volume>, <fpage>348</fpage>–<lpage>363</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">12916575</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref015"><label>15</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Chambers</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gullone</surname> <given-names>E</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Allen</surname> <given-names>NB</given-names></name> (<year>2009</year>) <article-title>Mindful emotion regulation: An integrative review</article-title>. <source>Clinical Psychology Review</source>, <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>560</fpage>–<lpage>572</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2009.06.005" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.cpr.2009.06.005</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">19632752</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref016"><label>16</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Campbell-Sills</surname> <given-names>L</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Barlow</surname> <given-names>DH</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Brown</surname> <given-names>TA</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hofmann</surname> <given-names>SG</given-names></name> (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>Effects of suppression and acceptance on emotional responses of individuals with anxiety and mood disorders</article-title>. <source>Behaviour Research and Therapy</source>, <volume>44</volume>, <fpage>1251</fpage>–<lpage>1263</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16300723</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref017"><label>17</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murakami</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaga</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ohira</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name> (<year>2009</year>) <article-title>Association of serotonin transporter gene polymorphism and emotion regulation</article-title>. <source>Neuroreport</source>, <volume>20</volume>, <fpage>414</fpage>–<lpage>418</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1097/WNR.0b013e328325a910" xlink:type="simple">10.1097/WNR.0b013e328325a910</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">19223791</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref018"><label>18</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Tang</surname> <given-names>YY</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Posner</surname> <given-names>MI</given-names></name> (<year>2013</year>) <article-title>Special issue on mindfulness neuroscience</article-title>. <source>Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</source>, <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>1</fpage>–<lpage>3</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/scan/nss104" xlink:type="simple">10.1093/scan/nss104</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">22956677</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref019"><label>19</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Creswell</surname> <given-names>JD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Way</surname> <given-names>BM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Eisenberger</surname> <given-names>NI</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lieberman</surname> <given-names>MD</given-names></name> (<year>2007</year>) <article-title>Neural correlates of dispositional mindfulness during affect labeling</article-title>. <source>Psychosomatic Medicine</source>, <volume>69</volume>, <fpage>560</fpage>–<lpage>565</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">17634566</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref020"><label>20</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Way</surname> <given-names>BM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Creswell</surname> <given-names>JD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Eisenberger</surname> <given-names>NI</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lieberman</surname> <given-names>MD</given-names></name> (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>Dispositional mindfulness and depressive symptomatology: Correlations with limbic and self-referential neural activity during rest</article-title>. <source>Emotion</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>12</fpage>–<lpage>24</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1037/a0018312" xlink:type="simple">10.1037/a0018312</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">20141298</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref021"><label>21</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>LeDoux</surname> <given-names>JE</given-names></name> (<year>2000</year>) <article-title>Emotion circuits in the brain</article-title>. <source>Annual Review of Neuroscience</source>, <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>155</fpage>–<lpage>184</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">10845062</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref022"><label>22</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Das</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kemp</surname> <given-names>AH</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Liddell</surname> <given-names>BJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Brown</surname> <given-names>KJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Olivieri</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Peduto</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2005</year>) <article-title>Pathways for fear perception: modulation of amygdala activity by thalamo-cortical systems</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>26</volume>, <fpage>141</fpage>–<lpage>148</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15862214</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref023"><label>23</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Roy</surname> <given-names>AK</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Shehzad</surname> <given-names>Z</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Margulies</surname> <given-names>DS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kelly</surname> <given-names>AM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Uddin</surname> <given-names>LQ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gotimer</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2009</year>) <article-title>Functional connectivity of the human amygdala using resting state fMRI</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>45</volume>, <fpage>614</fpage>–<lpage>626</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.11.030" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.11.030</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">19110061</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref024"><label>24</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Stein</surname> <given-names>JL</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wiedholz</surname> <given-names>LM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Bassett</surname> <given-names>DS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Weinberger</surname> <given-names>DR</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Zink</surname> <given-names>CF</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Mattay</surname> <given-names>VS</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>A validated network of effective amygdala connectivity</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>36</volume>, <fpage>736</fpage>–<lpage>745</lpage>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref025"><label>25</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Quirk</surname> <given-names>GJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Garcia</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>González-Lima</surname> <given-names>F</given-names></name> (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>Prefrontal mechanisms in extinction of conditioned fear</article-title>. <source>Biological Psychiatry</source>, <volume>60</volume>, <fpage>337</fpage>–<lpage>343</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16712801</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref026"><label>26</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Etkin</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Egner</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kalisch</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></name> (<year>2011</year>) <article-title>Emotional processing in anterior cingulate and medial prefrontal cortex</article-title>. <source>Trends in Cognitive Science</source>, <volume>15</volume>, <fpage>85</fpage>–<lpage>93</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2010.11.004" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.tics.2010.11.004</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">21167765</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref027"><label>27</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Goldin</surname> <given-names>PR</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>McRae</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ramel</surname> <given-names>W</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gross</surname> <given-names>JJ</given-names></name> (<year>2008</year>) <article-title>The neural bases of emotion regulation: reappraisal and suppression of negative emotion</article-title>. <source>Biological Psychiatry</source>, <volume>63</volume>, <fpage>577</fpage>–<lpage>586</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">17888411</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref028"><label>28</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hayes</surname> <given-names>JP</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Morey</surname> <given-names>RA</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Petty</surname> <given-names>CM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Seth</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Smoski</surname> <given-names>MJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>McCarthy</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>Staying cool when things get hot: emotion regulation modulates neural mechanisms of memory encoding</article-title>. <source>Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</source>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>230</fpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2010.00230" xlink:type="simple">10.3389/fnhum.2010.00230</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">21212840</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref029"><label>29</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ohira</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Nomura</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ichikawa</surname> <given-names>N</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Isowa</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Iidaka</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sato</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>Association of neural and physiological responses during voluntary emotion suppression</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>29</volume>, <fpage>721</fpage>–<lpage>733</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16249100</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref030"><label>30</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Vrtička</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sander</surname> <given-names>D</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Vuilleumier</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name> (<year>2011</year>) <article-title>Effects of emotion regulation strategy on brain responses to the valence and social content of visual scenes</article-title>. <source>Neuropsychologia</source>, <volume>49</volume>, <fpage>1067</fpage>–<lpage>1082</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2011.02.020" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2011.02.020</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">21345342</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref031"><label>31</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Curtis</surname> <given-names>CE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>D'Esposito</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name> (<year>2003</year>) <article-title>Persistent activity in the prefrontal cortex during working memory</article-title>. <source>Trends in Cognitive Science</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>415</fpage>–<lpage>423</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">12963473</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref032"><label>32</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Gianaros</surname> <given-names>PJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Van Der Veen</surname> <given-names>FM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Jennings</surname> <given-names>JR</given-names></name> (<year>2004</year>) <article-title>Regional cerebral blood flow correlates with heart period and high-frequency heart period variability during working-memory tasks: Implications for the cortical and subcortical regulation of cardiac autonomic activity</article-title>. <source>Psychophysiology</source>. <volume>41</volume>, <fpage>521</fpage>–<lpage>530</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15189475</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref033"><label>33</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Fairclough</surname> <given-names>SH</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Houston</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name> (<year>2004</year>) <article-title>A metabolic measure of mental effort</article-title>. <source>Biological Psychology</source>, <volume>66</volume>, <fpage>177</fpage>–<lpage>190</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15041139</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref034"><label>34</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bokde</surname> <given-names>AL</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Dong</surname> <given-names>W</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Born</surname> <given-names>C</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Leinsinger</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Meindl</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Teipel</surname> <given-names>SJ</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2005</year>) <article-title>Task difficulty in a simultaneous face matching task modulates activity in face fusiform area</article-title>. <source>Cognitive Brain Research</source>, <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>701</fpage>–<lpage>710</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16325382</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref035"><label>35</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Pezawas</surname> <given-names>L</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Meyer-Lindenberg</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Drabant</surname> <given-names>EM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Verchinski</surname> <given-names>BA</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Munoz</surname> <given-names>KE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kolachana</surname> <given-names>BS</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2005</year>) <article-title>5-HTTLPR polymorphism impacts human cingulate-amygdala interactions: a genetic susceptibility mechanism for depression</article-title>. <source>Nature Neuroscience</source>, <volume>8</volume>, <fpage>828</fpage>–<lpage>834</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15880108</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref036"><label>36</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Anticevic</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Brumbaugh</surname> <given-names>MS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Winkler</surname> <given-names>AM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lombardo</surname> <given-names>LE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Barrett</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Corlett</surname> <given-names>PR</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2013</year>) <article-title>Global prefrontal and fronto-amygdala dysconnectivity in bipolar I disorder with psychosis history</article-title>. <source>Biological Psychiatry</source>, <volume>73</volume>, <fpage>565</fpage>–<lpage>573</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2012.07.031" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.biopsych.2012.07.031</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">22980587</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref037"><label>37</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Erk</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Mikschl</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Stier</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ciaramidaro</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gapp</surname> <given-names>V</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Weber</surname> <given-names>B</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>Acute and sustained effects of cognitive emotion regulation in major depression</article-title>. <source>Journal of Neuroscience</source>, <volume>30</volume>, <fpage>15726</fpage>–<lpage>15734</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1856-10.2010" xlink:type="simple">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1856-10.2010</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">21106812</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref038"><label>38</label><mixed-citation publication-type="book" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lang</surname> <given-names>PJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Bradley</surname> <given-names>MM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Cuthbert</surname> <given-names>BN</given-names></name> (<year>1995</year>) <source>International Affective Picture System (IAPS)</source>. <publisher-name>National Institute of Mental Health Center for the Study of Emotion and Attention</publisher-name>, <publisher-loc>Bethesda, MD</publisher-loc>.</mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref039"><label>39</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murakami</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaga</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ohira</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name> (<year>2010</year>) <article-title>Phasichart rate responses for anticipated threat situations</article-title>. <source>International Journal of Psychophysiology</source>, <volume>77</volume>, <fpage>21</fpage>–<lpage>25</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2010.03.012" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.ijpsycho.2010.03.012</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">20381547</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref040"><label>40</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ogawa</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Lee</surname> <given-names>TM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kay</surname> <given-names>AR</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Tank</surname> <given-names>DW</given-names></name> (<year>1990</year>) <article-title>Brain magnetic resonance imaging with contrast dependent on blood oxygenation</article-title>. <source>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, U.S.A.</source>, <volume>87</volume>, <fpage>9868</fpage>–<lpage>9872</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">2124706</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref041"><label>41</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Ochsner</surname> <given-names>KN</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ray</surname> <given-names>RD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname> <given-names>JC</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Robertson</surname> <given-names>ER</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Chopra</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gabrieli</surname> <given-names>JD</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2004</year>) <article-title>For better or for worse: neural systems supporting the cognitive down- and up-regulation of negative emotion</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>483</fpage>–<lpage>499</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15488398</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref042"><label>42</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Bush</surname> <given-names>G</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Luu</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Posner</surname> <given-names>MI</given-names></name> (<year>2000</year>) <article-title>Cognitive and emotional influences in anterior cingulate cortex</article-title>. <source>Trends in Cognitive Science</source>, <volume>4</volume>, <fpage>215</fpage>–<lpage>222</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">10827444</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref043"><label>43</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lane</surname> <given-names>RD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Reiman</surname> <given-names>EM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Axelrod</surname> <given-names>B</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Yun</surname> <given-names>LS</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Holmes</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Schwartz</surname> <given-names>GE</given-names></name> (<year>1998</year>) <article-title>Neural correlates of levels of emotional awareness. Evidence of an interaction between emotion and attention in the anterior cingulate cortex</article-title>. <source>Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>525</fpage>–<lpage>535</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">9712681</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref044"><label>44</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Craig</surname> <given-names>AD</given-names></name> (<year>2009</year>) <article-title>How do you feel--now? The anterior insula and human awareness</article-title>. <source>Nature Reviews Neuroscience</source>, <volume>10</volume>, <fpage>59</fpage>–<lpage>70</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nrn2555" xlink:type="simple">10.1038/nrn2555</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">19096369</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref045"><label>45</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Critchley</surname> <given-names>HD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wiens</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Rotshtein</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ohman</surname> <given-names>A</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Dolan</surname> <given-names>RJ</given-names></name> (<year>2004</year>) <article-title>Neural systems supporting interoceptive awareness</article-title>. <source>Nature Neuroscience</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>189</fpage>–<lpage>195</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">14730305</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref046"><label>46</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hölzel</surname> <given-names>BK</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ott</surname> <given-names>U</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gard</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hempel</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Weygandt</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Morgen</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2008</year>) <article-title>Investigation of mindfulness meditation practitioners with voxel-based morphometry</article-title>. <source>Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience</source>, <volume>3</volume>, <fpage>55</fpage>–<lpage>61</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/scan/nsm038" xlink:type="simple">10.1093/scan/nsm038</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">19015095</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref047"><label>47</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lazar</surname> <given-names>SW</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kerr</surname> <given-names>CE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wasserman</surname> <given-names>RH</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Gray</surname> <given-names>JR</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Greve</surname> <given-names>DN</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Treadway</surname> <given-names>MT</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2005</year>) <article-title>Meditation experience is associated with increased cortical thickness</article-title>. <source>Neuroreport</source>, <volume>16</volume>, <fpage>1893</fpage>–<lpage>1897</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16272874</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref048"><label>48</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Murakami</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Nakao</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Matsunaga</surname> <given-names>M</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kasuya</surname> <given-names>Y</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Shinoda</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Yamada</surname> <given-names>J</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2012</year>). <article-title>The structure of mindful brain</article-title>. <source>PLOS ONE</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>e46377</fpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0046377" xlink:type="simple">10.1371/journal.pone.0046377</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">23029500</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref049"><label>49</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Geschwind</surname> <given-names>N</given-names></name> (<year>1970</year>) <article-title>The organization of language and the brain</article-title>. <source>Science</source>, <volume>170</volume>, <fpage>940</fpage>–<lpage>4</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">5475022</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref050"><label>50</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Hirano</surname> <given-names>S</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Naito</surname> <given-names>Y</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Okazawa</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Kojima</surname> <given-names>H</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Honjo</surname> <given-names>I</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ishizu</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>1997</year>) <article-title>Cortical activation by monaural speech sound stimulation demonstrated by positron emission tomography</article-title>. <source>Experimental Brain Research</source>, <volume>113</volume>, <fpage>75</fpage>–<lpage>80</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">9028776</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref051"><label>51</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Xiao</surname> <given-names>Z</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname> <given-names>JX</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wang</surname> <given-names>X</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Wu</surname> <given-names>R</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hu</surname> <given-names>X</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Weng</surname> <given-names>X</given-names></name>, <etal>et al</etal>. (<year>2005</year>) <article-title>Differential activity in left inferior frontal gyrus for pseudowords and real words: an event-related fMRI study on auditory lexical decision</article-title>. <source>Human Brain Mapping</source>, <volume>25</volume>, <fpage>212</fpage>–<lpage>221</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">15846769</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref052"><label>52</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Renaud</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Blondin</surname> <given-names>JP</given-names></name> (<year>1997</year>) <article-title>The stress of Stroop performance: physiological and emotional responses to color-word interference, task pacing, and pacing speed</article-title>. <source>International Journal of Psychophysiology</source>, <volume>27</volume>, <fpage>87</fpage>–<lpage>97</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">9342640</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref053"><label>53</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Cavanna</surname> <given-names>AE</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Trimble</surname> <given-names>MR</given-names></name> (<year>2006</year>) <article-title>The precuneus: a review of its functional anatomy and behavioural correlates</article-title>. <source>Brain</source>, <volume>129</volume>, <fpage>564</fpage>–<lpage>583</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">16399806</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref054"><label>54</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Aue</surname> <given-names>T</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Hoeppli</surname> <given-names>ME</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Piguet</surname> <given-names>C</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Sterpenich</surname> <given-names>V</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Vuilleumier</surname> <given-names>P</given-names></name> (<year>2013</year>) <article-title>Visual avoidance in phobia: particularities in neural activity, autonomic responding, and cognitive risk evaluations</article-title>. <source>Frontiers in Human Neuroscience</source>, <volume>7</volume>, <fpage>194</fpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00194" xlink:type="simple">10.3389/fnhum.2013.00194</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">23754994</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref055"><label>55</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Quirk</surname> <given-names>GJ</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Likhtik</surname> <given-names>E</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Pelletier</surname> <given-names>JG</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Paré</surname> <given-names>D</given-names></name> (<year>2003</year>) <article-title>Stimulation of medial prefrontal cortex decreases the responsiveness of central amygdala output neurons</article-title>. <source>Journal of Neuroscience</source>, <volume>23</volume>, <fpage>8800</fpage>–<lpage>8807</lpage>. <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">14507980</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
<ref id="pone.0128005.ref056"><label>56</label><mixed-citation publication-type="journal" xlink:type="simple"><name name-style="western"><surname>Lane</surname> <given-names>RD</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>McRae</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Reiman</surname> <given-names>EM</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Chen</surname> <given-names>K</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Ahern</surname> <given-names>GL</given-names></name>, <name name-style="western"><surname>Thayer</surname> <given-names>JF</given-names></name> (<year>2009</year>) <article-title>Neural correlates of heart rate variability during emotion</article-title>. <source>NeuroImage</source>, <volume>44</volume>, <fpage>213</fpage>–<lpage>222</lpage>. <comment>doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.07.056" xlink:type="simple">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2008.07.056</ext-link></comment> <object-id pub-id-type="pmid">18778779</object-id></mixed-citation></ref>
</ref-list>
</back>
</article>